Subqueries can be used in several places within a query.
يمكن استخدام الاستعلامات الفرعية في عدة أماكن داخل الاستعلام.
It can really be used anywhere you might use
يمكن استخدامها بالفعل في أي مكان قد يمكنكم استخدام
a table name or even a column name or an individual value.
اسم الجدول أو حتى اسم العمود أو قيمة فردية.
They're especially useful in conditional logic,
فهي مفيدة خاصة في المنطق الشرطي
in conjunction with where or Join clauses,
جنبًا إلى جنب مع شروط where أو Join،
or in the when portion of a case statement.
أو في جزء when من بيان الحالة.
For example, you might want to return only orders
على سبيل المثال، ربما تريد فقط إرجاع الأوامر
that occurred in the same month as Parch and Posies first order ever.
التي حدثت في نفس الشهر مثل أول أمر لقاعدتي بيانات Parch وPosies.
To get the date of the first order,
للحصول على تاريخ أول أمر،
you can write a subquery with a min function.
يمكنكم كتابة استعلام فرعي مع دالة min.
Let's add a date_trunc function to get the month.
لنضيف دالة date_trunc لنحصل على الشهر.
Finally, let's write an outer query that
أخيرًا، لنكتب استعلام خارجي
uses this to filter the orders table and sorts by the occurred at column.
يستخدم هذا لتصفية جدول الأوامر ويرتبها حسب حدوثها في العمود.
You can see that all of these orders took place in December 2013,
يمكنكم ملاحظة أن كل هذه الأوامر حدثت في ديسمبر 2013،
the same month as the first order.
نفس الشهر كأول أمر.
This query works because the result of the subquery is only one cell.
يعمل هذا الاستعلام لأن نتيجة الاستعلام الفرعي هي خلية واحدة فقط.
Most conditional logic will work with subqueries containing one-cell results.
سيعمل معظم المنطق الشرطي مع الاستعلامات الفرعية التي تحتوي على نتائج في خلية واحدة.
But IN is the only type of conditional logic
لكن IN هو نوع المنطق الشرطي الوحيد
that will work when the inner query contains multiple results.
الذي يعمل عندما يحتوي الاستعلام الداخلي على عدة نتائج.